psi.org 2019-12-26

# Privacy Notice : PSI

**Privacy Notice PSI.org**  

At PSI, we’re committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Notice explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure. 

We may change this Notice from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re aware of any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Notice. 

Any questions regarding this Notice and our privacy practices should be sent by email to info@psi.org or by writing to Legal Department at PSI, 1120 19th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20036.  Alternatively, you can telephone 202.785.0072. 

**Who are we?**  

We’re PSI, a global non-profit health organization, making it easier for people in the developing world to lead healthier lives and plan the families they desire. PSI is a tax-exempt, nonprofit organization, organized and existing under the laws of the State of North Carolina, USA. Our headquarters address is 1120 19th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20036.  The PSI network includes more than 50 countries in the developing world. 

**How do we collect information from you?**  

We obtain information about you when you use our website, for example, when you make a donation or if you register to receive one of our newsletters or announcements or if you access information we post about our programs. 

**What type of information is collected from you?**  

The personal information we collect might include your name, address, email address, IP address, and information regarding what pages are accessed and when. If you make a donation online, your payment information is not held by us. It is collected by our third party payment processors, who specialize in the secure online capture and processing of credit/debit card transactions, as explained below. 

**How is your information used?**  

We may use your information to: 

  * process a donation that you have made; 
  * process your entry into a competition; 
  * seek your views or comments on the services we provide; 
  * notify you of changes to our services; 
  * send you communications which you have requested and that may be of interest to you. These may include information about campaigns, appeals, other fundraising activities, or relevant work from our projects and partners; 
  * process a job application. 

We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis. We are legally required to hold some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations. We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with us. 

**Who has access to your information?**  

We will not sell or rent your information to third parties. 

We will not share your information with third parties for marketing purposes. 

Third Party Service Providers working on our behalf: We may pass your information to our third party service providers, agents, subcontractors and other associated organizations for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf (for example to process donations and send you mailings). However, when we use third party service providers, we disclose only the personal information that is necessary for them to deliver the service and we have a contract in place that requires them to keep your personal information secure and not to use it for their own direct marketing purposes. Please be assured that we will not release your personal information to third parties for them to use for their own direct marketing purposes unless you have requested us to do so, or we are required to do so by law, for example, by a court order or for the purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime. 

When you are using our secure online donation pages, your donation is processed by a third party payment processor, who specializes in the secure online capture and processing of credit/debit card transactions. If you have any questions regarding secure transactions, please contact us. 

**Your choices**  

You have a choice about whether or not you wish to receive information from us. If you do not want to receive direct communications from us about the vital work in which PSI engages, then you can select your choices by ticking the relevant boxes situated on the form on which we collect your information. 

We will not contact you for marketing purposes by email, phone or text message unless you have given your prior consent. We will not contact you for marketing purposes by post if you have indicated that you do not wish to be contacted. You can change your marketing preferences at any time by contacting us by email: info@psi.org , or telephone: 202.785.0072 (ask for External Relations and Communications). 

**How you can access and update your information**  

The accuracy of your information is important to us. We’re working on ways to make it easier for you to review and correct the information that we hold about you. In the meantime, if you change your email address, or any of the other personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or out of date, please email us at: info@psi.org, or write to us at: PSI External Relations and Communications Coordinator, 1120 19th Street, NW, Washington, DC 20036. Alternatively, you can telephone 202.785.0072 (ask for External Relations and Communications). 

You also have the right to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you, to request that we transfer your personal information to you or to another data processor, to request that we dispose of your personal information if we are legally permitted to do so, and to withdraw your consent for us to hold your personal information.   

**Security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information**  

When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure that it’s treated securely. Any sensitive information (such as credit or debit card details) is encrypted and protected with ￼Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) / Transport Layer Security. When you are on a secure page, a lock icon will appear on the bottom of web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer. 

Non-sensitive details (your email address etc.) are transmitted normally over the Internet, and this can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. Where we have given (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

**Profiling**  

We may analyze your personal information to create a profile of your interests and preferences so that we can contact you with information relevant to you. We may make use of additional information about you when it is available from external sources to help us do this effectively. We may also use your personal information to detect and reduce fraud and credit risk. 

**Use of ‘cookies’**  

Like many other websites, the PSI website uses cookies. ‘Cookies’ are small pieces of information sent by an organization to your computer and stored on your hard drive to allow that website to recognize you when you visit. They collect statistical data about your browsing actions and patterns and do not identify you as an individual. For example, we use cookies to store the pages you may visit. This helps us to improve our website and deliver a better more personalized service.  

The best way to switch off cookies is by setting  ** _your_**  browser preferences. For more information on how to switch off cookies on your computer, visit our [full cookies policy](https://www.psi.org/about/about-cookies-policy/). Turning cookies off may result in a loss of functionality when using our website. 

**Links to other websites**  

Our website may contain links to other websites run by other organizations. This Privacy Notice applies only to our website‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you access them using links from our website. 

In addition, if you linked to our website from a third party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the Notice of that third party site. 

**16 or Under**  

We are concerned to protect the privacy of children aged 16 or under. If you are aged 16 or under‚ please get your parent/guardian’s permission before you provide us with personal information. 

**Transferring your information outside of Europe**  

If you have accessed this website while within the European Union (“EU”), you should be aware that the information which you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the EU. By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EU. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the EU. By submitting your personal data, you’re agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing. If we transfer your information outside of the EU in this way, we will take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are taken with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Notice. 

If you use our services while you are outside the EU, your information may be transferred outside the EU in order to provide you with those services.

**Analytics**  

Our website uses analytics, ￼which may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, page scrolling and any text keyed into website forms. The information collected does not include bank details or any sensitive personal data. Data collected by these tools is for PSI’s internal use only. The information collected is used to improve our website usability and is stored and used for aggregated and statistical reporting.

**Review of this Notice**  

We keep this Notice under regular review. This Notice was last updated on May 25, 2018.
